# Jorge Sánchez

#### Game Programmer

<b>♠</b> Website	<b>■</b> Email	<b>○</b> Github	<b>└</b> Phone	<b>i</b> LinkedIn
<u>jsanchez.net</u>	<u>jsanchezsilvera@gmail.com</u>	<u>jsancheznet</u>	+59897991380	<u>jsancheznet</u>

#### About me:

I am a game programmer with a solid foundation in C/C++, complemented by hands-on experience with Unreal Engine. I also write engine and rendering code with OpenGL for personal enjoyment.

Outside of work, you'll catch me buried in technical books about the nuts and bolts of game tech. When I'm not geeking out over low-level code, I'm usually playing games that inspire me to pick up my keyboard every day.

# **Experience:**

2022-2023 | Game Programmer at Nimble Giant Entertainment.

- Gameplay Programmer on a VR title using Unreal Engine
  - Developed and maintained the game's tutorial throughout the entire project.
  - o Designed and implemented the game's Al using behavior trees.
  - Crafted and brought to life several additional gameplay features.
- Platforms Programmer on a unannounced FPS game using Unreal Engine
  - Implemented automation tests using Unreal Engine's automation system.

### 2013-2022 | Sysadmin/Developer at Madolsur.

- Created sales and marketing tools to send promotions and billing information to our customers.
- Developed tools to check for synchronization errors between our online services and the internal billing and stock software.
- Developed and maintained the company's e-commerce website.
- Inherited, extended, and managed existing network infrastructure with 5 branch offices.
  Installed and configured mail(Zimbra/iRedMail), database(MySQL) and web servers(LEMP).
- Provided technical support to the company and customers.
- Integrated Mercado Libre (South American eBay) with the company's existing software, publishing, updating, and maintaining more than 1500 products which led to increased sales both online and in-person.
- Managed and monitored the company's social media marketing campaigns.

# 2012-2013 | Sysadmin/Developer at Cemisold SA.

Development and maintenance of interactive messaging services.

# Skills:

- Programming Languages: C, C++
- Graphics Libraries: OpenGL
- Unreal Engine
- Debugging
- Object Oriented Programming.
- Procedural Programming.
- Linux server administration

• Emacs, Perforce, Git, RenderDoc, Unix/Linux, Windows Visual Studio.

# Languages:

- Spanish (Native).
- English (Advanced, C2).

# **Programming projects:**

- Glow is a top-down shooter written in C++ with OpenGL, libSDL, FreeType, glad, and stb\_image.
  - Forward renderer, Bloom, HDR, Gamma Correction, Resizable framebuffers.
  - 2D & 3D text rendering.
  - Collision detection & resolution by SAT algorithm.
  - Random number generator based on XorShift.
  - Debug mode. Move the camera around and debugging data is printed on the screen.
- **≯isanchez\_math** is my personal game dev math library, written in C and C++
  - 2, 3, and 4-dimensional vector support.
  - 4x4 matrix functions and operators.
  - Camera and projection functions.
  - General utility functions include remapping a range, converting to radians, and more.
- **♠ isanchez.net** is my personal website, you will find more projects and some articles there.

## **Education:**

- 2024 | Professional Game Development in C++ and Unreal Engine Tom Looman.
- 2013 | Ruby on Rails Tealeaf Academy.
- 2013 | Core Ruby Curriculum Tealeaf Academy.
- 2009 | Red Hat Linux System Administration (RH133) Red Hat Bs.As.
- 2009 | Red Hat Linux Essentials (RH033) Red Hat Bs.As.
- 2008 | Linux System Administration O'Reilly School of technology.

### **References:**

### Fabián Domínguez

Lead Programmer, team leader at Nimble Giant Entertainment.

Email: fabian.dominguez@nimblegiant.com

Telephone: +54 9 11 2691-3584

# **Carol Soler**

Sales representative, colleague in Madolsur SA.

Email: carolsoler09@gmail.com Telephone: +598 98 702 900